<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>[ robot ] + [ machine ]</title>
    <description>This is a place on the internet where someone you probably don&#39;t know writes words.
</description>
    <link>https://robotmachine.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://robotmachine.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 15:04:29 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 15:04:29 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week my wife and I decided to move from Eugene, Oregon to my home town of Lexington, South Carolina.&lt;br&gt;
The decision didn&amp;#39;t come lightly at first, but the longer I think on it the more I feel that it is simply the right thing to do for our family.&lt;br&gt;
Some back story: In 2003 I was nineteen years old and my then-girlfriend (now ex-wife) decided that she was going to move to Santa Barbara, CA to go to a photography school. Rather than discussing it with me, I was simply told that she was going to do this. The sentiment was very much &amp;quot;... and you can come if you want ...&amp;quot; &amp;mdash; which didn&amp;#39;t sit well with me. In an effort to convince myself that this was my choice, I immediately began to dæmonise the south and over-inflate my anger/disquiet/&amp;amp;c. To put it simply, it being out of my control caused me to spin out of control and rush head-long in to the move at any cost in an effort to save face.&lt;br&gt;
Once I arrived in Santa Barbara, I quickly burned through the money I had just keeping a roof over our head. We quickly were living off student loans and grants as well as borrowing money from family. Thankfully, the relationship ended in 2007.&lt;br&gt;
I was living by myself at that point in an apartment. Several friends of mine were living in a shared house nearby, so I moved in with them. It was there that I met Channing. We started dating and moved to her parents house (rent in Santa Barbara is impossibly high) and married a year after our first date. From there a child seemed to be the obvious choice, but a family in Southern California seemed unmanageable. Especially considering our desire for her to stay home with the kids while I worked from home.&lt;br&gt;
We had taken a trip north to Portland, OR and we really liked it there. So, Oregon became the destination. First, we lived in Newport, Oregon where Odin was born. Just before he turned one we moved to Eugene, OR so we could live in a more populous area. When Odin was 2.5 years old we had our second son, Opal. When the decision to move to South Carolina was made we had been in Oregon for around four years.&lt;br&gt;
In that time we had made friends, but we just had not found the comfort that we were hoping to have. A lot of it is just who we are as people, but it doesn&amp;#39;t change the outcome. Once the idea to move back implanted itself, all around me I felt that our eldest son was missing out on interaction with other people. My mother came to visit in June of 2015 and Channing&amp;#39;s family visited in September and during both visits Odin seemed to experience great personal growth. Suddenly he began approaching other children at the park to play with them instead of only playing when pursued. It seemed like happiness.&lt;br&gt;
South Carolina has a lot to offer our family and I&amp;#39;m excited to make the move. In addition to having family the cost of living is even lower than in Eugene&amp;mdash; which was already much lower than Santa Barbara. My hope is that we will soon be able to have a much easier and simpler life for our family.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://robotmachine.github.io/blog/2015/10/06/Moving.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://robotmachine.github.io/blog/2015/10/06/Moving.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>G2M Removal Tool</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Supported Products:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoToMeeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoToWebinar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoToTraining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Citrix Launcher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just need to download the tool? &lt;a href=&quot;https://citrix.sharefile.com/d-s73538a0c6f0445eb&quot;&gt;Click Here&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;CHANGELOG&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;24 July, 2015&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;mdfind&lt;/code&gt; to find any stray GoToMeeting.app files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;22 July, 2015:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quits GoToMeeting and GoToMeeting Recording Manager if they are open&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using an array for plists to avoid errors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;17 July, 2015:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added to version control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://robotmachine.github.io/projects/2015/07/17/GoToMeeting-Removal-Tool.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://robotmachine.github.io/projects/2015/07/17/GoToMeeting-Removal-Tool.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Smiths</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was about 14 I started listening to metal and punk almost exclusively. The loud, sloppy, noisy, and angry kind. The stuff that sounds good when you are a kid and parents just don&amp;#39;t understand. Since I was a certified poseur I also read all of the rock and punk magazines that I could get my hands on. Despite my South Carolina public school education I was able to read the interviews and could even glean common points that the musicians would bring up. There were bands that would be mentioned as influences and, even though I didn&amp;#39;t know them, I could at least name drop and pretend that their first album was good. At some point I noticed that a lot of the punk bands mentioned some band called The Smiths. I had no idea who they were, but if all of these cool punk guys like them, then surely they must be punk as fuck.&lt;br&gt;
Since this was the late 90s I went to a thing called a record store. I went to my old familiar punk section and recited the alphabet quietly to myself and found the S section. And then the SMs. But where The Smiths should have been, they were not. After repeating the alphabet several times and making quite certain that I had it right I decided they might be a metal band after all. No. Not in metal. I took a deep breath and went and found the guy who works in the record store really hoping that he wouldn&amp;#39;t murder me for not knowing where The Smiths are categorised.&lt;br&gt;
I explained that I wanted to buy a CD of The Smiths, but I couldn&amp;#39;t find it for some reason. He was only a little snarky and dragged me past the metal section, past the punk, and right over to the section that I had never allowed myself to get close to... POP. I thought &amp;quot;What is going on here? This can&amp;#39;t be right.&amp;quot;, but alas. There was the plastic divider clearly labelled The Smiths. He then said &amp;quot;Do you know what you want?&amp;quot; and I confessed that I didn&amp;#39;t know them. He handed me &amp;#39;Meat Is Murder&amp;#39; and said &amp;quot;I like this one.&amp;quot; If you don&amp;#39;t know the album, the cover has a soldier with &amp;#39;Meat Is Murder&amp;#39; handwritten on his helmet. Looked punk enough. Maybe it was in pop because they were older? I didn&amp;#39;t know, but I did know I was about to have an experience once I got home-- my car only had an AM/FM radio.&lt;br&gt;
As soon as I arrived home I took the plastic off the case and put it in my CD player. I distinctly remember waiting for a second before hitting play. From the first note in &lt;em&gt;The Headmaster Ritual&lt;/em&gt; I was sure there was some mistake. There was another band called The Smiths. They were underground and even the best record store in Columbia didn&amp;#39;t have them in stock.  Whatever The Smiths were, this was not them. Of that much I could be sure.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://robotmachine.github.io/blog/2015/06/30/Smiths.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://robotmachine.github.io/blog/2015/06/30/Smiths.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Big Brother</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On 21 October our second child was born. We named him Opal Poseidon. Opal is calm and completely at peace with the world that surrounds him— no matter how boisterous that world may be. As the one in the room onto which the title of &amp;#39;adult&amp;#39; is bestowed, this brings me near to the point of sneering at times. His lack of panic shines a bright light on my own neurotic and frantic disposition. I feel out of place in the world and it has never been more clear as when looking in the face of a few-day-old human that simply cannot be troubled. On its own, this would have only minor impact on me; I am the adult, after all, and I have never before let complete panic and insanity keep me from pretending that I know what is going on. The real struggle is with our eldest son, Óðinn. On the whole he is so very wonderful for a two and a half year old person. Helpful, caring, doting on his brother. Everything that you could want and then more. Yet, he has deep and real frustration that seeps to the surface so easily. It is so simple to &amp;quot;just know&amp;quot; that he will be fine— and he really will be— and still it feels like a cheat. The desire is to overcome. Not only deal with trouble as it comes, but defeat it. Know his pain, take it in, understand it, find a resolution, and express to him only the most perfect empathy. The sort of supernatural moment that involves ones hair turning colours and light beaming from mysterious sources. This is the hope. Difficulty comes in the outbursts and tantrums. Unexpected and seemingly impossible to understand or conquer. &amp;quot;Why have I failed?&amp;quot; is the chorus. &amp;quot;In what way have I failed to meet this small and fragile person&amp;#39;s needs?&amp;quot; The answer that I hesitate to allow myself is that these are just the breaks. This is what happens when you disrupt someone&amp;#39;s life. It isn&amp;#39;t fair or just or right, but neither is it unfair or unjust or wrong. It is literally life. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://robotmachine.github.io/blog/2014/06/15/Big-Brother.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://robotmachine.github.io/blog/2014/06/15/Big-Brother.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scrabble</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems that at some point everyone says (at least to themselves) that if only TROUTING were a word they would be up 61 points. Could I play it off? Try, like Kramer, to use it in a sentence and trick my opponent? (&amp;quot;Quone. To quone something. Well, you won&amp;#39;t find it in there, you need a medical dictionary!&amp;quot;) Or, better yet, &amp;quot;I am only two letters and a place to play it from spelling NUTRITION!&amp;quot; Much the same way that you are a million dollars shy of having $1,000,048. &amp;quot;What is the point, really?&amp;quot; That is where it goes. Looming over any game of chance or skill is the spectre of another existential crisis. &amp;quot;Why does any of this matter!?&amp;quot; you&amp;#39;ll think. This game will be where nihilism or entropy or apathy will finally get the best of you. You have staved it off a long while. It has earned it by now. You knew this day was coming. Close your eyes and let the destruction take hold. It will be over soon. No looking back now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://robotmachine.github.io/blog/2014/06/15/Scrabble.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://robotmachine.github.io/blog/2014/06/15/Scrabble.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>QuickLedger</title>
        <description>&lt;h4&gt;Install&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/robotmachine/QuickLedger/tarball/master&quot;&gt;the archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;chmod +x ql&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move &lt;code&gt;ql&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/bin/&lt;/code&gt; or somewhere else in &lt;code&gt;$PATH&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Usage&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time you run &lt;code&gt;ql&lt;/code&gt; it will try to figure out where your Ledger data file is located based on &lt;code&gt;$LEDGER&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;$LEDGER_FILE&lt;/code&gt; environment variables and store this in a ~/.qlrc file. If nothing is found, it will just ask you.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;usage: ql [-h] [-f LEDGER_FILE] [-a ACCOUNT] [-m MERCHANT] [-c CATEGORY]
          [-e EXPENSE] [-t AMOUNT] [-s] [-x] [--list] [--set-acct]
          [--set-merch] [--set-cat] [--config ALT_CONFIG] [-v]

QuickLedger: Entry creation utility for http://ledger-cli.org

optional arguments:
  -h, --help            show this help message and exit
  -f LEDGER_FILE, --file LEDGER_FILE
                        Specify Ledger data file.
  -a ACCOUNT, --account ACCOUNT
                        Specify account.
  -m MERCHANT, --merchant MERCHANT
                        Set merchant.
  -c CATEGORY, --category CATEGORY
                        Set transaction category.
  -e EXPENSE, --expense EXPENSE
                        Set expense category. (Prepends &#39;Expenses:&#39;
  -t AMOUNT, --amount AMOUNT
                        Set transaction amount.
  -s, --split           Split payment.
  -x, --not-cleared     Mark transaction as not-cleared/pending.
  --list                List settings in config file.
  --set-acct            Set up accounts in config file.
  --set-merch           Set up merchants in config file.
  --set-cat             Set up categories in config file.
  --config ALT_CONFIG   Specify alternate config file.
  -v, --version         Print version.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Configuration File&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ql&lt;/code&gt; keeps all data in &lt;code&gt;$HOME/.qlrc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Here is a sample of what one might look like:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$&amp;gt; cat ~/.qlrc&lt;/code&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;[file]  
ledger_file = /home/robotmachine/doc/Ledger.dat  

[account]
default_account = CHEQ 
CHEQ = Assets:MyBank:Chequing  
SAVE = Assets:MyBank:Savings  

[merchant]  
SD = Sundance Natural Foods  
SQ = SeQUential Biofuels  

[category]
groc = Expenses:Groceries
SD = Expenses:Groceries  
SQ = Expenses:Auto:Fuel  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ~/.qlrc file can be manually edited or you can use the various setup options, --set-acct, --set-cat, --set-merch to have &lt;code&gt;ql&lt;/code&gt; add them to ~/.qlrc for you.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Usage Continued&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When using the &lt;code&gt;ql -a ACCOUNT&lt;/code&gt; option, &lt;code&gt;ql&lt;/code&gt; will attempt to match the entry with one of the accounts in the [account] section of ~/.qlrc If a match is not found, the literal string will be used.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same is true of the &lt;code&gt;ql -m MERCHANT&lt;/code&gt; option. If a match is found for the merchant and the same entry is present under [category], then the category will be used. If that does not match, then it will prompt interactively for an expense category.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The -s/--split option will take the -t amount as the total (or prompt for one) and prompt through splitting the transaction between multiple categories (see example). &lt;code&gt;ql&lt;/code&gt; does its best to make sure the transaction will balance and will add the total as a negative balance which will cause an error in &lt;code&gt;Ledger&lt;/code&gt; if the amounts do not reconcile. Entering a 0 for any of the splits will use the remainder of the balance.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The -x/--not-cleared option will use a ! instead of * between the date and the merchant as per the &lt;code&gt;Ledger&lt;/code&gt; documentation to mark the transaction as not cleared. Please see &lt;code&gt;Ledger&lt;/code&gt; documentation on how this works. Note: You will need to manually edit your ledger.dat file to mark it as cleared. Re-running &lt;code&gt;ql&lt;/code&gt; without the -x will not mark the transaction as cleared-- it will only add an additional entry for the same amount.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Examples&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone loves examples. The above .qlrc file is assumed for the examples.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ql -m SD -t 27.50&lt;/code&gt; will append the following to /home/robotmachine/doc/Ledger.dat  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;2014-11-01 * Sundance Natural Foods  
    Expenses:Groceries      $27.50  
    Assets:MyBank:Chequing  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Split Transaction&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ql -m SD -t 100&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;Total is $100.00  
Enter &#39;0&#39; for the remainder.  

Enter amount for split number 1:        $75  
Enter category for split number 1:      Expenses:Expenses:Groceries  

$25.00 remaining.  
Enter amount for split number 2:        $0  
Enter category for split number 2:      Expenses:Heathcare:Supplements  

Wrote entry to /home/robotmachine/doc/Ledger.dat:  
2014-12-27 * Sundance Natural Foods 
        Expenses:Heathcare:Supplements  $25.00    
        Expenses:Groceries              $75.00  
        Assets:MyBank:Chequing          $-100.00  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://robotmachine.github.io/projects/2014/05/14/ql.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://robotmachine.github.io/projects/2014/05/14/ql.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RoboTag</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Dependencies:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eyed3.nicfit.net&quot;&gt;eyeD3&lt;/a&gt; v0.7.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imagemagick.org&quot;&gt;Image Magick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sahib/glyr&quot;&gt;glyr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How It Works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;rt&lt;/code&gt; uses file names, directory names, and metadata files to create ID3v2 tags on MP3 files. The goal is to create clean tags without unwanted junk in them without having to go full manual. As an added bonus the use of metadata files allows non Latin characters to be stored safely outside of filenames while still resulting in properly spelled tags.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;rt&lt;/code&gt; expects a directory structure where an Artist Name directory contains Album Name directories which then contain MP3 files. An example of the full path to the fifth track on the second disc of Radiohead&amp;#39;s 2007 album &amp;quot;In Rainbows&amp;quot; would be as follows:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;/home/brian/music/Radiohead/2007 In Rainbows/02-05 Last Flowers.mp3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;rt&lt;/code&gt; is run from inside the Album Name folder and will find MP3 files located within.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Metadata Files&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A metadata file inside of the Album Name folder will supersede a metadata file of the same name in the Artist Name directory. (ie. If both &lt;code&gt;2007 In Rainbows/.genre.txt&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Radiohead/.genre.txt&lt;/code&gt; exist in the example above, the data from &lt;code&gt;2007 In Rainbows/.genre.txt&lt;/code&gt; will be used.&lt;br&gt;
Only the first line is read for files that are only meant to contain a single value (ie. .artist.txt). Any additional data is ignored.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;.album.txt&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contains the title of the album.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;.albumartist.txt&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contains the name to be used in the Album Artist field.&lt;br&gt;
Example usage: Thee Silver Mt. Zion Memorial Orchestra has used several different names for various releases, but you don&amp;#39;t want them randomly sorted everywhere. Album Artist is supported by most MP3 players and will allow all releases to be sorted together, but display the right artist name for the release.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;.artist.txt&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contains the artist name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;.genre.txt&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contains the genre name for the artist or album.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;.tracks01.txt; tracks02.txt; &amp;amp;c&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title of the album tracks. The first line corresponds to the first track and so on. In the event of a multi-disc album, the metadata file should be .tracks01.txt, tracks02.txt and so on.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Locations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Within the Artist Name folder, the following metadata files are supported:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.artist.txt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.genre.txt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Within the Album Name folder, the following metadata files are supported:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.album.txt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.albumartist.txt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.artist.txt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.genre.txt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.tracks01.txt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.year.txt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://robotmachine.github.io/projects/2014/03/01/rt.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://robotmachine.github.io/projects/2014/03/01/rt.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&amp;#211;&amp;#240;inn</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My son&amp;#39;s name is Odin. We normally use the Old Norse spelling of &amp;#211;&amp;#240;inn.&lt;br&gt;
When we say his name, though, we just say Odin (&lt;em&gt;Oh-den&lt;/em&gt;), but a lot of people ask about the Norse spelling.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;#211; is said the same as if you were to exclaim &lt;em&gt;Oh!&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;#208;&amp;#240; is called &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C3%90&quot;&gt;eth&lt;/a&gt; and is said &lt;em&gt;th&lt;/em&gt; as in fa &lt;em&gt;th&lt;/em&gt; er.&lt;br&gt;
Putting it all together, you would say &amp;#211;&amp;#240;inn as &lt;em&gt;Oh-then&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
You can hear a computer say it &lt;a href=&quot;http://translate.google.com/#en/is/Odin&quot;&gt;on Google Translate&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://robotmachine.github.io/blog/2013/03/13/Odin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://robotmachine.github.io/blog/2013/03/13/Odin.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PushText</title>
        <description>&lt;h4&gt;Installation:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/robotmachine/PushText/tarball/master&quot;&gt;the archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;chmod +x pt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move &lt;code&gt;pt&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/bin&lt;/code&gt; or somewhere else in &lt;code&gt;$PATH&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Configuration:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you run &lt;code&gt;pt&lt;/code&gt; without any setup it will ask for your API token and your user key.&lt;br&gt;
The user key is on your &lt;a href=&quot;http://pushover.net&quot;&gt;user page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
You must create an application with Pushover in order to send messages.&lt;br&gt;
See &lt;a href=&quot;https://pushover.net/apps&quot;&gt;Pushover Apps&lt;/a&gt; for more information.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Examples:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simplest example would be to let you know when something finishes on your computer.
&lt;code&gt;$&amp;gt; make ; make install ; pt --title &amp;quot;make&amp;quot; --message &amp;quot;Done compiling.&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The above will result in this on your phone:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://mlkshk.com/r/L2TK.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pt example&quot; title=&quot;pt example&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could also use it to let you know if something breaks.
&lt;code&gt;$&amp;gt; some script ; if [ &amp;quot;$?&amp;quot; -ne &amp;quot;0&amp;quot; ]; then pt -m &amp;quot;Oops, you bwoke it.&amp;quot; ; fi&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send your &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ginatrapani/todo.txt-cli&quot;&gt;Todo.txt&lt;/a&gt; list daily:
&lt;code&gt;bash
$&amp;gt; crontab -l | grep pt
30 10 * * * /usr/local/bin/pt --title &amp;quot;Todo&amp;quot; -m &amp;quot;`/usr/local/bin/todo ls`&amp;quot; -d iphone
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The possibilities are endless! (As long as the possibilities only include sending messages to your phone.)  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Manual:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;usage: pt [-h] [-u USER_KEY] [-t TOKEN_KEY] [-p PRIORITY] [-m MESSAGE]
          [-d DEVICE] [--title TITLE] [--url URL] [--urltitle URL_TITLE] [-v]

PushText: Command line tool for http://pushover.net

optional arguments:
  -h, --help            show this help message and exit
  -u USER_KEY, --user-key USER_KEY
                        User key instead of reading from settings.
  -t TOKEN_KEY, --token-key TOKEN_KEY
                        Token key instead of reading from settings.
  -p PRIORITY, --priority PRIORITY
                        Set priority of high or low. Default is normal.
  -m MESSAGE, --message MESSAGE
                        Message to send. Default is &quot;PushText&quot;
  -d DEVICE, --device DEVICE
                        Device name to receive message. Default sends to all
                        devices.
  --title TITLE         Title or application name. Default is PushText
  --url URL             Optional URL to accompany your message.
  --urltitle URL_TITLE  Title to go with your URL.
  -v, --version         Print version.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://robotmachine.github.io/projects/2012/10/23/pt.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://robotmachine.github.io/projects/2012/10/23/pt.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GoToLogFiles</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Supported Products:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoToMeeting/GoToWebinar/GoToTraining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoToMyPC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoToAssist Corporate &amp;amp; Remote Support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ShareConnect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just need to download the tool? &lt;a href=&quot;https://citrix.sharefile.com/d-s4aa711b3b514e928&quot;&gt;Click Here&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;CHANGELOG&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;17 August, 2015 (v 1.2):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ShareConnect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;20 July, 2015 (v 1.1):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drastically cut down scripting-- down to a single file&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoToMyPC host and client merged to one entry&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoToAssist RS and Corp merged to one entry&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User prompt now built in to shell script&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desktop folder is popped after log file collection&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;13 July, 2015 (v 0.9):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Printing plist files to text files&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;26 June, 2015 (v 0.8):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cut down on redundant scripting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a start.sh and finish.sh for all logging that is common to all products&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rewrote Voltron to use a function to reduce redundancy&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;25 June, 2015 (v 0.6):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplified output of ps for running process log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;diskutil list&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;df -H&lt;/code&gt; logging to Disk_Info.txt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;11 March, 2015 (v 0.5):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed GoToMeeting Recording logs as they are no longer needed&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File name now has a Unix Epoch date stamp to avoid globbed files&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the logs are collected, a prompt notifies that the process is complete&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Samples are collected of the GoToMeeting EP and RecMgr if they are running&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://robotmachine.github.io/projects/2012/09/03/GoToLogFiles.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://robotmachine.github.io/projects/2012/09/03/GoToLogFiles.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
