<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brian&#39;s Bullshit Words</title>
    <description>This is a place on the internet where someone you probably don&#39;t know writes words.
</description>
    <link>http://silenceisdefeat.net/~robotmachine/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://silenceisdefeat.net/~robotmachine/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 09:22:43 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 09:22:43 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Smiths</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was about 14 I started listening to metal and punk almost exclusively. The loud, sloppy, noisy, and angry kind. The stuff that sounds good when you are a kid and parents just don’t understand. Since I was a certified poseur I also read all of the rock and punk magazines that I could get my hands on. Despite my South Carolina public school education I was able to read the interviews and could even glean common points that the musicians would bring up. There were bands that would be mentioned as influences and, even though I didn’t know them, I could at least name drop and pretend that their first album was good. At some point I noticed that a lot of the punk bands mentioned some band called The Smiths. I had no idea who they were, but if all of these cool punk guys like them, then surely they must be punk as fuck.&lt;br /&gt;
Since this was the late 90s I went to a thing called a record store. I went to my old familiar punk section and recited the alphabet quietly to myself and found the S section. And then the SMs. But where The Smiths should have been, they were not. After repeating the alphabet several times and making quite certain that I had it right I decided they might be a metal band after all. No. Not in metal. I took a deep breath and went and found the guy who works in the record store really hoping that he wouldn’t murder me for not knowing where The Smiths are categorised.&lt;br /&gt;
I explained that I wanted to buy a CD of The Smiths, but I couldn’t find it for some reason. He was only a little snarky and dragged me past the metal section, past the punk, and right over to the section that I had never allowed myself to get close to… POP. I thought “What is going on here? This can’t be right.”, but alas. There was the plastic divider clearly labelled The Smiths. He then said “Do you know what you want?” and I confessed that I didn’t know them. He handed me ‘Meat Is Murder’ and said “I like this one.” If you don’t know the album, the cover has a soldier with ‘Meat Is Murder’ handwritten on his helmet. Looked punk enough. Maybe it was in pop because they were older? I didn’t know, but I did know I was about to have an experience once I got home– my car only had an AM/FM radio.&lt;br /&gt;
As soon as I arrived home I took the plastic off the case and put it in my CD player. I distinctly remember waiting for a second before hitting play. From the first note in &lt;em&gt;The Headmaster Ritual&lt;/em&gt; I was sure there was some mistake. There was another band called The Smiths. They were underground and even the best record store in Columbia didn’t have them in stock.  Whatever The Smiths were, this was not them. Of that much I could be sure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 02:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://silenceisdefeat.net/~robotmachine/stories/2015/06/30/Smiths.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://silenceisdefeat.net/~robotmachine/stories/2015/06/30/Smiths.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scrabble</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems that at some point everyone says (at least to themselves) that if only TROUTING were a word they would be up 61 points. Could I play it off? Try, like Kramer, to use it in a sentence and trick my opponent? (“Quone. To quone something. Well, you won’t find it in there, you need a medical dictionary!”) Or, better yet, “I am only two letters and a place to play it from spelling NUTRITION!” Much the same way that you are a million dollars shy of having $1,000,048. “What is the point, really?” That is where it goes. Looming over any game of chance or skill is the spectre of another existential crisis. “Why does any of this matter!?” you’ll think. This game will be where nihilism or entropy or apathy will finally get the best of you. You have staved it off a long while. It has earned it by now. You knew this day was coming. Close your eyes and let the destruction take hold. It will be over soon. No looking back now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2014 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://silenceisdefeat.net/~robotmachine/games/2014/06/15/Scrabble.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://silenceisdefeat.net/~robotmachine/games/2014/06/15/Scrabble.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>games</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Big Brother</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On 21 October our second child was born. We named him Opal Poseidon. Opal is calm and completely at peace with the world that surrounds him— no matter how boisterous that world may be. As the one in the room onto which the title of ‘adult’ is bestowed, this brings me near to the point of sneering at times. His lack of panic shines a bright light on my own neurotic and frantic disposition. I feel out of place in the world and it has never been more clear as when looking in the face of a few-day-old human that simply cannot be troubled. On its own, this would have only minor impact on me; I am the adult, after all, and I have never before let complete panic and insanity keep me from pretending that I know what is going on. The real struggle is with our eldest son, Óðinn. On the whole he is so very wonderful for a two and a half year old person. Helpful, caring, doting on his brother. Everything that you could want and then more. Yet, he has deep and real frustration that seeps to the surface so easily. It is so simple to “just know” that he will be fine— and he really will be— and still it feels like a cheat. The desire is to overcome. Not only deal with trouble as it comes, but defeat it. Know his pain, take it in, understand it, find a resolution, and express to him only the most perfect empathy. The sort of supernatural moment that involves ones hair turning colours and light beaming from mysterious sources. This is the hope. Difficulty comes in the outbursts and tantrums. Unexpected and seemingly impossible to understand or conquer. “Why have I failed?” is the chorus. “In what way have I failed to meet this small and fragile person’s needs?” The answer that I hesitate to allow myself is that these are just the breaks. This is what happens when you disrupt someone’s life. It isn’t fair or just or right, but neither is it unfair or unjust or wrong. It is literally life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2014 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://silenceisdefeat.net/~robotmachine/kids/opal/2014/06/15/Big-Brother.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://silenceisdefeat.net/~robotmachine/kids/opal/2014/06/15/Big-Brother.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>kids</category>
        
        <category>opal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&amp;#211;&amp;#240;inn</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My son’s name is Odin. We normally use the Old Norse spelling of Óðinn.&lt;br /&gt;
When we say his name, though, we just say Odin (&lt;em&gt;Oh-den&lt;/em&gt;), but a lot of people ask about the Norse spelling.&lt;br /&gt;
Ó is said the same as if you were to exclaim &lt;em&gt;Oh!&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Ðð is called &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C3%90&quot;&gt;eth&lt;/a&gt; and is said &lt;em&gt;th&lt;/em&gt; as in fa &lt;em&gt;th&lt;/em&gt; er.&lt;br /&gt;
Putting it all together, you would say Óðinn as &lt;em&gt;Oh-then&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
You can hear a computer say it &lt;a href=&quot;http://translate.google.com/#en/is/Odin&quot;&gt;on Google Translate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://silenceisdefeat.net/~robotmachine/kids/odin/2013/03/13/Odin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://silenceisdefeat.net/~robotmachine/kids/odin/2013/03/13/Odin.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>kids</category>
        
        <category>odin</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
